我以为在这个星球上是禁止使用武器的
I thought weapons were forbidden on this planet.
再说了...
Besides...
...我不相信你会为了这片荒地而把我杀了
..I can't believe you'd kill me for a field of empty holes.
这是我唯一拥有的
It's all I have.
你的内心非常痛苦  关于我的痛苦你知道些什么?
Your pain runs deep. What do you know of my pain?
让我们...  一起来探索
Let us explore it...together.
每个人心中都隐藏着一种神秘的痛苦
Each man hides a secret pain.
我们必须揭开它的面纱  正视它
It must be exposed and reckoned with.
我们必须把它从黑暗拽进光明
It must be dragged from the darkness into the light.
分享你的痛苦  让我分享你的痛苦
Share your pain. Share your pain with me
并从分享之中获得力量
and gain strength from the sharing.
你从哪里获得这种能力的?
Where did you get this power?.
这种能力就在你心中
The power was within you.
我感觉如释重负
It is as if a weight has been lifted from my heart.
我可以怎么报答你?  加入我的探寻之旅
How can I repay you? Join my quest.
你在探寻什么?  就是你所探寻的
What is it you seek?. What you seek.
自从世界起源以来人们一直在探寻的
What all men have sought since time began.
终极的学识
The ultimate knowledge.
我们需要一艘星舰才能去探寻
To find it we need a starship.
星舰?  祥云III星球上没有星舰
A starship? There are no starships on Nimbus Ill.
我有办法弄一艘来  什么办法?
I have a way to bring one here. But how?.
要有信心  我的朋友
Have faith, my friend.
我们有很多人  比你知道的多得多
There are more of us than you know.
你是个瓦肯人
You're a Vulcan.
星际迷航5:  终极先锋
约塞米蒂国家公园  地球
星历8454.1
你会在登陆假期中玩得很愉快的  老骨头
'You'll have a great time on shore leave, Bones."
你可以好好放松放松
'You'll be able to relax."
你把这叫做放松?  我紧张得要命呢
You call this relaxing? I'm a nervous wreck.
如果不注意点  我可能会疯掉的
If I'm not careful, I'll end up talking to myself.
你好  舰长
Greetings, Captain.
史波克  你在这儿干嘛?  我在监视你的进展
Spock, what are you doing here? I'm monitoring your progress.
我真是受宠若惊
I'm flattered,
但公园里有这么多有趣的景点
but of all the points of interest here
为什么偏偏到我这儿来?
why pick me?
埃尔卡普坦峰的攀登纪录是无人能破的
The record for climbing EI Capitan is in no danger of being broken.
我这么做是因为我喜欢爬山
I'm doing this because I enjoy it.
更不用说最重要的原因...  什么原因?
Not to mention the most important reason for climbing a mountain...
因为山在你面前
Because it's there.
我不认为你意识到了自己现在有多危险
I do not think you realise the gravity of your situation.
恰恰相反  危险性是我最关心的问题
On the contrary, gravity is foremost on my mind.
我要继续往上爬了  你去找麦考依医生唠叨吧
I'm trying to make an ascent. Go pester Dr McCoy.
麦考依医生现在心情不好
Dr McCoy is not in the best of moods.
不负责任的混蛋!
Goddamn irresponsible...!
简直是玩命
Playing games with life.
一定要集中精力  你必须人石合一
Concentration is vital. You must be one with the rock.
如果你继续烦我的话...
If you don't stop distracting me...
也许山在你面前这个爬山理由并不充分
Perhaps "because it is there" is not sufficient reason to climb a mountain.
我不得不同意你的说法
I am hardly in a position to disagree.
嗨  老骨头  一起吃晚饭吧?
Hi, Bones. Mind if we drop in for dinner?.
祥云III星球  天堂城
先生们  我叫凯瑟琳・达尔
I am Caithlin Dar.
对!  罗幕兰的新代表
Yes! Our new Romulan representative.
欢迎来到天堂城  银河和平之星的首都
Welcome to Paradise City, capital of the Planet of Galactic Peace.
我是圣约翰・陶博特  祥云III星球的联邦代表
I'm St John Talbot, the Federation Representative here on Nimbus Ill.
我的这位富有魅力的伙伴是克林贡领事  考德
My charming companion is the Klingon Consul, Korrd.
我猜这就是克林贡人打招呼的方式  请进  亲爱的
I expect that's Klingon for hello. Come in, my dear.
20年前  我们三族政府共同商定开发这个星球
20 years ago, our three governments agreed to develop this planet.
一个新时代由此诞生了  但很快就结束了
A new age was born. It died a quick death.
被我们骗到这里的移民很快变得好斗起来
The settlers we conned into coming here took to fighting.
我们没收了他们的武器  但他们却开始自行制造
We forbad them weapons, but they fashioned their own.
看来我来得正是时候
It appears I've arrived just in time.
离那发报机远点
Get away from that transmitter.
罗幕兰人
Romulan.
地球人
Terran.
克林贡人
Klingon.
你们已成为我的俘虏  俘虏?
Consider yourselves my prisoners. Prisoners?
我们早已成为这片荒土的俘虏
We're already prisoners here on this worthless lump of rock.
我们对你有什么价值?  祥云III星球是一片荒土
What value could we be to you? Nimbus Ill is a worthless lump of rock.
但整个银河系也只有这地方  会同时出现你们三个
But it is the only place in the galaxy that has the three of you.
我们的政府会不惜一切代价保护我们的
Our governments will stop at nothing to ensure our safety.
这正是我所期望的
That's exactly what I'm counting on.
USS  进取号试航报告
USS Enterprise, shakedown cruise report.
我想这船是猴子们组装起来的
I think this new ship was put togetherbymonkeys.
有半数的门开不了  猜猜谁来做修理工作?
Halfthe doors won't open, and guess whosejob itis to make itright?
混蛋!
Borgus frat!
让我们看看她有些什么能耐
"Let's see what she's got,
史考提  我们都看到了  对吧?
Scotty." We found out, didn't we?
我相信你一定能把她驯服的
I know you'll whip her into shape.
乌拉我以为你休假去了
Uhura, I thought you were on leave.
我想我们应该一起去休假的
I thought we were going together.
进取号需要我的时候我是不会离开她的
I can't leave her when she needs me.
我就知道你会这么说的
I had a feeling you would say something like that.
所以我把晚餐带来了
So I brought us dinner.
你是我认识的最善解人意的女人
You're the most understanding woman I know.
红色警报
Red alert.
我刚修好那该死的东西!
I just fixed that damn thing!
关掉它  行吗?
Turn it off, will you?
红色警报
Red alert.
这是红色警报  进取号  收到请回答
This is a red alert. Enterprise, acknowledge.
这里是进取号  请说明你的身份
This is Enterprise. Identify yourself.
这里是星际舰队  在中立区出现7级优先情况
This is Starfleet. We have a Priority 7 situation in the NeutraIZone.
史考提  这是来真的  不会吧!
Scotty, this is for real. They can't be serious!
这船现在七零八落的而且主要船员也没到齐
The ship's in pieces and we've got less than a skeleton crew.
星际舰队  知道我们当前的状况吗?
Starfleet, are you aware of our current status?
知道  准备接收行动命令并召回主要船员
Yes. Stand by to copy operational orders and recall key personnel.
承认吧  我们迷路了  对  但我们仍在加速前进
Admit it, we're lost. Yes, but we're making good time.
苏鲁中校  请回答  真难以置信
Commander Sulu, come in. I don't believe this.
登陆假期取消了
Shore leave is cancelled.
咱终于有救了  返回预定位置
Rescued at last. Return to pre-arranged co-ordinates.
你不能说我们迷路了  有问题吗?
You can't say we're lost. Is there a problem?
对  我们遇到了...  一场暴风雪
Yes. We've been caught in...a blizzard.
我们什么也看不见  请给我们指明方向
We can't see a thing. Direct us to the co-ordinates.
我这里显示天气晴朗  气温华氏70度
My visual says sunny skies and 70 degrees.
苏鲁看  太阳出来了  真是奇迹
Look, the sun has come out. It's a miracle.
别担心  我会保守你们这个秘密的  我会用穿梭机接你们
Don't worry, your secretis safe with me. I'll send the shuttle foryou.
乌拉  我欠你一个人情
Uhura, I owe you one.
快过来吃吧!
Come and get it!
老骨头  快别敲了
Bones, knock it off.
我们就在这儿而且饿死了
We're right here and we're starving.
彼泼德种子  医生?  豆子
Bipodal seeds, Doctor?.
史波克  但不是普通豆子
Beans, Spock, but no ordinary beans.
这是根据我父亲传给我的一个  古老食谱做出来的
These are from an old recipe handed down to me by my father.
如果你把你的瓦肯鼻子贴着这些...
If you stick your Vulcan nose up at these,
你真是麦考依家族中出言不逊的一代
you're insulting generations of McCoys.
这样的话我只好尝尝你的豆子了
In that case I have little choice but to sample your beans.
真是不错  它的确有一种我不熟悉的配料
Surprisingly good. It does have a flavouring I'm not familiar with.
那可是秘密配料  还有其他秘密配料吗  老骨头?
That's the secret ingredient. Any more secret ingredient, Bones?
请自便
Be my guest.
你的秘密配料就是酒?  威士忌  田纳西威士忌
Your secret ingredient is alcohol? Tennessee whiskey.
威士忌和豆子  真是劲爆组合  史波克能搞定它吗?
Bourbon and beans, an explosive combination. Can Spock handle it?
你开玩笑  以瓦肯人的新陈代谢能力
With that Vulcan metabolism,
一碗白蚁他也吃得下
he could eat a bowl of termites.
医生  我一半是人类  根本看不出来
Doctor, I am half-human. It certainly doesn't show.
谢谢  这家伙总是这样
Thank you. This guy never changes.
我取笑他  他却以为我在赞美他
I insult him and he takes it as a compliment.
你们两个真令人头疼  我怎么了?
You two could drive a man to drink. What did I do?
人的生命是那么宝贵  怎么可以那么疯狂地冒险呢?
Human life is far too precious to risk on crazy stunts.
你从那山上摔下来时会死的
You should have been killed when you fell off that mountain.
我确实想过这个
It did cross my mind.
但我知道即使摔下来我也不会死的
But even as I fell I knew I wouldn't die.
不是只有他才是永生的吗?  不  不是说这个
Isn't he the only one who's immortal? No, it isn't that.
我知道自己不会死是因为我有你们两个相伴
I knew I wouldn't die because the two of you were with me.
我不明白  我一直都知道...
I do not understand. I've always known...
...我会孤独地死去
..l'll die alone.
我会在瓦尔哈拉殿堂给你订个房间的
I'll call Valhalla and reserve a room for you.
到时候我们一起在太空  不断地相互打趣...
All that time in space, getting on each others nerves...
那么登陆假期时我们干什么呢?  我们一起度假
So what do we do on shore leave? We spend it together.
其他人都有家庭  其他人  我们没有
Other people have families. Other people, not us.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我准备烤一个沼泽甜瓜
I'm preparing to toast a "marsh melon".
真有你的!  沼泽甜瓜  你哪里学来的?
I'll be damned! A marsh melon. Where did you learn to do that?
我了解过野营方面的一些习俗
I have familiarised myself with the customs associated with camping out.
我们烤完沼泽甜瓜之后干什么?
What do we do after we toast the marsh melon?
吃掉它们  不  我是说在那以后
We consume them. No, I mean after that.
我们应该进行一个叫作大伙齐欢唱的仪式
We are required to engage in a ritual known as the sing-along.
自从我还是个爱荷华州的小男孩以来
I haven't sung around the campfire
一直没有再绕着篝火唱过歌了
since I was a boy in lowa.
我们唱什么呢?
What are we going to sing?
康城赛马  收拾起你的烦恼
"Camptown Races." "Pack up your troubles."
我们要走了吗?  这是一首歌的名字
Are we leaving? It's a song title.
莱久7星球上的月亮  划呀划  来划船
"Moon over Rigel 7." "Row, row, row your boat."
你知道《划呀划  来划船》吗?  我没研究过它
Do you know "Row your boat"? It didn't come up in my research.
歌词很简单...
The lyrics are very simple...
划呀划  来划船  缓缓地顺流而下
"Row, row, row your boat gently down the stream.
欢快地  欢快地  欢快地  欢快地划
"Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily,
人生只是一场梦
life is but a dream."
医生和我先唱  然后你加入进来
The Doctor and I will start off and you jump in.
医生  你先请  别说我没警告过你（我唱不好）
Doctor, if you please. Don't say I didn't warn you.
史波克  你为什么不加入进来?  我不理解歌词
Spock, why didn't you jump in? I cannot comprehend the words.
这只是首歌  你这个绿血的瓦肯人  歌词并不重要
It's a song, you green-blooded Vulcan. The words aren't important.
你只要唱得高兴就够了  对不起  医生
You just have a good time singing. I am sorry, Doctor.
我们唱歌的时候很高兴吗?  我比较喜欢死而复生之前的他
Were we having a good time? I liked him better before he died.
我们还是睡觉吧
Let's just get some sleep.
舰长...  我们在休假  叫我吉姆
Captain... We're on leave. Call me Jim.
吉姆...  什么事  史波克?
Jim... Yes, Spock?.
人生不是一场梦
Life is not a dream.
睡觉吧  史波克  是  舰长
Go to sleep, Spock. Yes, Captain.
晚安  老骨头  晚安  吉姆
Good night, Bones. Good night, Jim.
晚安  史波克  晚安  医生
Good night, Spock. Good night, Doctor.
晚安  史波克  晚安  吉姆
Good night, Spock. Good night, Jim.
我不明白  我就是不明白
I don't know. I just don't know.
卡拉舰长  发现一个古老的深空探测卫星
Captain Klaa, we have the target in sight. A probe ofancient origin.
很难摧毁吗?  很难
Difflcult to hit? Most difflcult.
好  所有武器由我控制
Good. All weapons atmy control.
观察镜
Scope.
射击太空垃圾不足以考验战士的勇气
Shooting space garbage is no test ofa warrior's mettle.
我需要一个会还击的目标
I need a target thatfilghts back.
舰长  收到新资料  祥云III星球有人被劫持
Captain, new data, hostages on Nimbus Ill.
其中一个是克林贡人  其他的呢?
One ofthe hostages is a Klingon. And the others?
一个地球人和一个罗幕兰人
A Terran and a Romulan.
联邦一定会派出星舰营救他们
The Federation will be sending a rescue ship ofits own.
设定航线前往祥云III星球
Plot course forNimbus Ill.
我一直想跟联邦星舰交手
I've always wanted to engage a Federation ship.
那该死的光别照我脸上
Get the damn light out of my face.
我们只能用穿梭机过来
We had to send the shuttlecraft.
传送机还无法运作
The transporter is non-operational.
我们收到了新命令  我带着通讯器呢
We have received new orders. I had my communicator.
你忘带了  真不知道我怎么会忘的
You forgot to take it with you. I wonder why I did that.
看来登陆假期取消了  收拾下垃圾
It appears shore leave has been cancelled. Pack out your trash.
我只渴望要一艘高大的船  以及一颗引航的星星相伴
"All I ask is a tall ship and a star to steer her by."
麦尔维尔  约翰・梅斯菲尔德
Melville. John Masefield.
你确定?  我十分精通经典作品
Are you sure about that? I'm well-versed in the classics.
那你怎么会不知道《划呀划  来划船》?
Then how come you don't know "Row, row, row your boat"?
进取号  下面由你控制  我们干得不错
Enterprise, you have control. We're doing just fine.
我只想说  他们不像以前那样造船了
All I can say is they don't make them like they used to.
你说过你能在两周内修好这艘船
You told me you could have this ship operational in two weeks.
我想你给我的时间太多了
I think you gave me too much time.
我得跟你们说多少次?  要合适的工具才能干好相应的工作
How many times do I have to tell you? The right tool for the right job.
我从没见他这么高兴过
I've never seen him happier.
舰桥...但愿能到达舰桥
Bridge...l hope.
我要先去淋浴
I could use a shower.
嗯
Yes.
这船上没一样东西能正常工作的吗?
Doesn't anything work on this ship?
他们不能叫我们这样去执行任务
They can't send us out like this.
星际舰队通讯当前在线  接到屏幕上
Starfleet transmission on line. Put it on the view screen.
请稍微安静点行吗?
Can we have a little quiet, please?
能调清楚点吗?
Can you clear that up?
能不能稍微安静点?
Can we have a little quiet?
鲍勃!  吉姆!
Bob! Jim!
怎么制服都没穿?  我正要去淋浴
We are dressing informally. I'm on my way to the shower.
很抱歉取消了你们的登陆假期
I apologise for cancelling shore leave.
在祥云III星出现危急情况
We have a dangerous situation out on Nimbus III.
银河和平之星上?
On the Planet of Galactic Peace?
一伙恐怖分子占领了唯一的居住区
A terroristforce has captured the only settlement.
他们抓了人质  克林贡  罗幕兰和联邦的三位领事
They've taken hostages. The Klingon, the Romulan, the Federation Consuls.
进取号还无法胜任...  进取号简直是在灾难中
The Enterprise is not up to specs... The Enterprise is a disaster.
我们在这象限中还有其他星舰  但是没有经验丰富的指挥官
We have ships in the quadrant. Butno experienced commanders.
我需要吉姆・柯克  拜托!
I need Jim Kirk. Please!
去祥云III星并评估那里的情况
Proceed to Nimbus Ill and assess the situation.
避免冲突
Avoid a confrontation.
但最重要的是  把那些人质安全地救回来
Above all, however, get those hostages back safely.
克林贡人有回应吗?  没有  但肯定会有的
Have the Klingons responded? No, butyou can bet they will.
设定航线前往祥云III  苏鲁先生  航线设定
Plot a course for Nimbus Ill, Mr Sulu. Course plotted.
我恐怕这艘船的毛病得在路上解决了
I'm afraid the ship's problems will have to be solved en route.
我希望你们每个人都尽力而为  我们开始干活吧
I'm counting on each one of you to give his best. Let's go to work.
吉姆  如果你问我  而你还没...
Jim, if you ask me, and you haven't...
我觉得这不是个好主意  我们肯定会碰上克林贡人的
I think this is a terrible idea. We're bound to bump into the Klingons.
而且他们真的不怎么喜欢你  彼此彼此
And they don't exactly like you. The feeling's mutual.
轮机舱  我们需要你能提供的全部动力
Engine room, we'll need all the power you can muster, mister.
就算我只能用双手推船
We'll beat those Klingon devils
我们也一定能打败那些克林贡魔鬼的
even if I have to get out and push.
我希望不要惨到那个样子
I hope it won't come to that.
尽可能以最快速度航行  苏鲁先生  是  长官
All possible speed, Mr Sulu. Aye, sir.
怎么了?  我怀念起我的旧椅子了
What's the matter?. I miss my old chair.
进取号奉命前往祥云III星球
The starship Enterprise has been dispatched to Nimbus Ill.
进取号?  那是柯克的星舰
Enterprise? That's Kirk's ship!
如果我能打败柯克...
Ifl could defeatKirk...
那你就是全银河最英勇的战士了
You would be the greatest warrior in the galaxy.
全速前进  我们必胜
Maximum speed! Success!
舰长日志:  星历84...
Captain's log: Stardate 84...
(系统故障)
舰长日志:  星历84...
Captain's log: Stardate 84...
早上好  舰长  算了吧
Good morning, Captain. Forget it.
我们获得了有关人质的信息  显示到屏幕上
We have the hostage information. Put it on the screen.
这是星际舰队资料库授权传输的资料
This is an authorised transmission from the Starfleetmemorybank.
怎么是考德将军!  显然他已不再受宠了
Not General Korrd! He's apparently fallen from favour.
考德的军事战略曾是学院的必修课
Korrd's military strategies were required learning at the Academy.
等他们逼我退休的时候  希望我下场能比他好点
When they put me out to pasture, I hope I fair better than Korrd.
这一定是人质的录像了
This must be the hostage tape.
不久前我们向银河光明之军投降了
A short time ago, we surrendered to the Galactic Army ofLight.
我们现在处在他们首领的保护性监禁之下
We are now in the protective custody oftheir leader.
只要我们合作就不会受到伤害
We will be treated humanely as long as we cooperate.
他要求你们立即派出一艘星舰来谈判释放我们的问题
He requests thatyou send a starship to parley for our release at once.
我们现在很好  如果你们能迅速作出答复我们将很感激
We are in good health and would appreciate your immediate response.
我很遗憾做出这样极端的事  但这是极端的时期
I regret this desperate act, but these are desperate times.
我无意伤害这些无辜者  但是不要考验我
I mean no harm to these innocents, but do notputme to the test.
我恳求你们立即回应
I implore you to respond immediately.
怎么了?
What is it?
你看起来像见了鬼似的  也许是的  舰长
You look like you've seen a ghost. Perhaps I have, Captain.
史波克  怎么了?  你认识这个瓦肯人?
Spock, what is it? Do you know this Vulcan?
我不确定  但他确实很眼熟?
I cannot be certain. But he does seem familiar?.
他使我想起了我年轻的时候认识的一个人
He reminds me of someone I knew in my youth.
我没听你说过  我不常回忆过去的
I didn't know you had one. I do not often think of the past.
他使你想起了谁?  一个才华横溢的年轻学生
Who does he remind you of? A gifted young student.
他很有智慧
He possessed a great intelligence.
他曾被认为能够成为伟大瓦肯学者团体中的一员
It was assumed that he would join the great scholars of Vulcan.
但他是个变革者  这是什么意思?
But he was a revolutionary. What do you mean?
他所寻求的学识是被瓦肯信仰所禁止的
The knowledge he sought was forbidden by Vulcan belief.
禁止?  他拒绝培养逻辑思维
Forbidden? He rejected his logical upbringing.
他信奉我们祖先那种野性的激情
He embraced the animal passions of our ancestors.
他相信自我认识的关键在于情感...  而不是逻辑
He believed the key to self-knowledge was emotion...not logic.
想想看  一个充满激情的瓦肯人
Imagine that, a passionate Vulcan.
当他开始鼓励其他人跟随他时  他被驱逐出瓦肯
When he encouraged others to follow him, he was banished from Vulcan.
真有意思
Fascinating.
舰长到舰桥来  我来了
Captain to the bridge. On my way.
史波克?  来了  舰长
Spock?. Coming, Captain.
正在靠近祥云III星球  标准轨道  苏鲁先生
Approaching Nimbus Ill. Standard orbit, Mr Sulu.
天堂城要求我们表明来意
Paradise City is demanding to know our intentions.
用静电噪音回复  让他们以为我们正遇到麻烦
Respond with static. Let them think we're having difficulty.
天堂城  我们难以接收清楚你们的讯息
Paradise City, we are barely receiving your transmission.
传送室  报告情况  传送机还无法使用
Transporter room, status. Transporter is still inoperative.
就算我们锁定了人质也无法把他们传送上来
If we could lock on to the hostages, we couldn't beam them up.
看来我们得自己去救他们了  克林贡战舰正在接近
We'll have to get them out ourselves. Klingon vessel approaching.
猛禽舰  1.9小时后她的武器进入射程
Bird of Prey. 1 .9 hours till her weapons are in range.
该死!  我们走
Damn! Let's go.
他们的扫描设备很简陋  但很有效
Their scanning equipment is primitive, but effective.
在坐标856.3登陆  那儿离城市很远
Land at co-ordinate 856.3. That's far from the city.
我们不能冒险被侦查到  苏鲁先生  执行命令
We cannot risk detection. Mr Sulu, execute.
这里是进取号星舰  联邦星舰
This is the starship Enterprise. A Federation starship.
我是帕维尔・契可夫舰长  你们违反了我们的协定
This is Captain Pavel Chekov. You are in violation ofour treaty.
立即释放人质否则将遭受严重后果
Release your hostages at once orsuffer the consequences.
你的威胁真好笑  什么后果?
Your threats amuse me. What consequences?
一艘克林贡战舰将在一小时内来到这儿
A Klingon warship will arrive within the hour.
克林贡人会十分生气  他们可能会摧毁这个星球
The Klingons will be quite angry. They are likely to destroy the planet.
那么我能受你和你的飞船保护真是太棒了
Then it is fortunate I have you and your starship to protect me.
你和你的大副传送到我指定的坐标上来
You and your first officer are to beam down to my co-ordinates.
我们很乐意传送下来  但我们必须能得到保证
We will be happy to beam down, but we musthave certain assurances.
步行到城市需要1.2小时
At foot speed, the journey to the city will take 1 .2 hours.
我们没有1.2小时
We don't have 1.2 hours.
等等...好极了!  我们得引起他们的注意
Wait a minute... Perfect! We'll have to get their attention.
那是什么?
What's that?
她是不是裸着身子?
Is she naked?
你好  小子
Hello, boys.
我一直希望能以歌声俘获人心
I've always wanted to play to a captive audience.
史波克  要人马合一  是  舰长
Spock, be one with the horse. Yes, Captain.
打开门  是我们的侦查队
Open the gate. It's our lookout party.
联邦士兵就在我们后面  关上门
Federation soldiers are right behind us. Close the gate.
他们要去哪儿?
Where are they going?
史波克...  停下你的马  我在做扫描
Spock... Hold your horse, I'm scanning.
人质在那座建筑物里
The hostages are being held in that structure.
加里利奥  开始行动
Galileo, start your run.
相位枪设定为击晕  苏鲁  打掉那灯
Phasers on stun. Sulu, take out that light.
怎么回事?  投降  你们正遭受攻击
What's going on? Surrender, you are under attack.
我并不想要流血冲突  等等!  回来
It wasn't bloodshed I wanted. Wait! Come back.
乌拉  快下来  收到  来了
Uhura, come on down. Roger, coming in.
祥云III以其野生动物而闻名
Nimbus Ill is famous forits wildllfe,
这里也是最棒的钓鱼之处!
and the flshing is terrifilc!
你可以很方便地在联邦政府资助下到达那里
Easy flnancing through Federation Federal can take you there.
谢天谢地  请合作
Thank God. Please cooperate.
交出你们的武器
Hand over your weapons.
干得好  我的朋友们!
Well done, my friends.
你是谁?
Qualse tu?
史波克!
Spock!
史波克  是我
Spock, it's me.
我是赛波克  你终于找到我了
It's Sybok. You've finally caught up with me.
难道你没什么要对我说的吗?
Don't you have anything to say to me?
你因违反17项中立区协定而被捕了
You are under arrest for 17 violations of the Neutral Zone Treaty.
史波克!  你终于有了点幽默感  我没和你开玩笑
You've developed a sense of humour. I did not intend to amuse you.
这些是很严肃的指控  但如果你现在投降...
These are serious charges. However, if you surrender now...
对不起  史波克  我还没违反全部的中立区协定
I'm sorry, Spock, I'm not through violating the Neutral Zone Treaty.
事实上  我才刚刚开始  我接下来要违反的是...
In fact, I'm just getting started. For my next violation,
我准备偷一样东西
I intend to steal something.
一样非常大的东西
Something very big.
我要你的飞船
Your starship.
你设计这一切就是为了偷到我的飞船?
You staged all this to get your hands on my ship?
你是谁?  詹姆斯T.柯克舰长
Who are you? Captain James T Kirk.
我以为契可夫舰长...  我明白了...很聪明  舰长
I thought Captain Chekov... I see... Very clever, Captain.
史波克  再给你一次加入我的机会
Spock, you have been given a second chance to join me.
我是一名星际舰队军官  当然
I am a Starfleet officer. Of course.
当然  那么我就不用你们帮忙  自己偷船了
Of course. Then I'll take the ship without your help.
穿梭机正在返回  猛禽舰的位置?
Shuttle en route. Position of Bird of Prey?.
接近中!
Closing!
距离射程还有约8000公里
Estimating attack range in 8,000 kellicams.
我们秘密行动  四分之一脉冲推进
Stealth approach, slow to one quarterimpulse power.
准备隐形  启动隐形装置
Prepare to cloak. Engage cloaking device.
猛禽舰肯定隐形了  升起护盾
The Bird of Prey must have cloaked. Raise shields.
穿梭机怎么办?  照做  进入红色警报
The shuttle...? Do it. Go to red alert.
当我们控制你的船以后  我们就把追随者们带上来
Once we control your vessel, we'll bring up our followers.
克林贡人就在那儿  我们能赶到飞船上就很幸运了
The Klingons are out there. We'll be lucky to make it to the ship.
这里是进取号  红色警报
This is Enterprise, red alert.
猛禽舰正在靠近  已升起护盾
Bird ofPrey approaching. Raising shields.
找一个安全的港口降落
Find a safe harbour.
不!
No!
不要回复  保持航线
No reply. Remain on course.
听我说  要让这艘小艇进入起降台
Listen to me. In order for this craft to enter the landing bay,
进取号就必须降下护盾  并激活牵引光束
Enterprise must lower the shields and activate the tractor beam.
重新升起护盾要花...  15.5秒
To re-raise the shields will take... 15.5 seconds.
我们在这么长的时间里将非常脆弱
An eternity, during which we'll be vulnerable to attack.
他说的是真话  如果我们的人隐形了  就表示要攻击了
He speaks the truth. If my people are cloaked, then they intend to strike.
我们不能回头  让我来做点什么
We cannot turn back. Let me do something.
好吧  做你必须做的  别耍花招
Very well, do what you must, but no more.
进取号  我是柯克
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
柯克  他在穿梭机上  快改变攻击航向
Kirk! He's on the shuttlecratf! Alter the attack course!
了解你们的处境  但我们不能返回行星
Understand your situation. Are unable to return to planet.
准备执行紧急降落计划...B
Stand by to execute emergency landing plan...B
紧急降落计划B?  B  就是barricade中的B
Emergency landing plan B? B as in barricade.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
为了快速降下和升起护盾  我们不使用牵引光束
In order to lower and raise the shields quickly, we'll forego the tractor beam.
我们将手动驾驶她
We'll fly her in manually.
你常这样做?  事实上  这是我第一次尝试
How often have you done this? Actually, it's my first attempt.
他很棒...真的
He's good...really.
史考提  打开起降台大门
Scotty, open bay doors.
准备解除隐形并开火
Stand by to de-cloak forflring.
史考提  降下护盾  正在降下护盾
Scotty, lower shields. Lowering shields.
猛禽舰方位105.2  前进  苏鲁
Bird of Prey bearing 105.2. Go, Sulu.
他们进来了
They're in.
瞄准进取号  已瞄准目标
Bear on Enterprise. Enterprise targeted!
进入曲速!  开火!
Warp speed now! Firing!
追踪他们的航线
Track her course!
他果然了得
He's good.
我们必须立即改变航线
We must change course at once.
我带你去舰桥
I'll take you to the bridge.
把枪捡起来
Pick it up.
赛波克...
Sybok...
你必须投降
You must surrender.
不!
No!
除非你杀了我  杀了他!
You must kill me. Shoot him!
有一会儿...我以为你真的会这么做
For a moment... I thought you might actually do it.
把他和柯克舰长一起关进牢房
Put him in the brig with Captain Kirk.
史波克  你愿意和我一起去舰桥吗?
Spock, you will accompany me to the bridge?
不...我不愿意
No...l will not.
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
那么你得跟他们一起去了
Then you must join them.
这两个会有用处的  让我们单独待一会儿
These two will be useful. Give us a moment alone.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
混蛋  史波克  你背叛了我们
Goddamn it, Spock. You betrayed us all.
我并不期望你原谅我
I do not expect you to forgive me.
我真应该狠揍一下你的屁股  如果你认为有用就随便
I ought to knock you on your ass. If you think it would help.
你要我把住他吗?  别插嘴...为什么?
You want me to hold him? Stay out of this... Why?.
你只需要扣一下扳机  那么赛波克就死了
All you had to do was pull the trigger. Then Sybok would be dead.
我命令你保护飞船  并且杀死我的兄弟
I ordered you to defend your ship. And kill my brother.
他是你的瓦肯伙伴并不等于他就是...
A fellow Vulcan is not a...
赛波克也是萨瑞克之子
Sybok also is a son of Sarek.
他真是你兄弟?  你瞎编
He's your brother brother?. You made that up.
我没瞎编  你没有兄弟
I did not. You don't have a brother.
严格说来我没有兄弟  看到了吧?
Technically I don't have a brother. See?
我有个同父异母的兄弟  我得坐坐
I have a half-brother. I've got to sit down.
你和赛波克的父亲是同一个  但母亲不同?
You and Sybok have the same father but different mothers?
赛波克的母亲是个瓦肯公主  但我们像亲兄弟那样长大的
Syboky mother was a Vulcan princess, but we were raised as brothers.
为什么你以前没告诉过我们?  这是私事
Why didn't you tell us this before? It is a personal matter.
对此我表示道歉  这样就能全部了结了  就一个道歉?
For that I am sorry. That makes everything all right. Sorry!
史波克不能杀他兄弟  就像不能杀你一样
Spock could no more kill his own brother than he could kill you.
他已经关进牢房里来了
He's already in the brig.
再说了  我们还有更重要的事要解决
Besides, we've got bigger problems to deal with.
比如我们怎么从这儿出去
Like how do we get out of here.
我得说  你总是令我感到惊奇
I'll say one thing, you never cease to amaze me.
我自己也是
Nor I myself.
我刚开始担心了  没关系  赛波克会解释的
I was beginning to worry. It's all right. Sybok will explain.
你在干什么?  设定新航线
What are you doing? Plotting our new course.
你没权这么做
You have no authority.
这是怎么了?  帕维尔  听他说
What's going on here? Pavel, listen to this man.
我不明白  每个人心中都隐藏着一种神秘的痛苦
I don't understand. Each of us hides a secret pain.
让我分享你的痛苦  你将从中获得力量
Share yours with me and gain strength from the sharing.
没有用
Useless.
不明智
Unwise.
你应该警告我的  肯定有办法出去
You could have warned me. There's got to be a way out.
这个新牢房能有效防止逃脱  你怎么知道?
This new brig is escape-proof. How do you know?.
设计师们找了最聪明的人来试着逃脱
The designers tested it using the most intelligent person they could find.
他失败了  这个人是不是长着尖耳朵的?
He failed to escape. Did this person have pointed ears?
并且总能够把他的同伴们拖入麻烦之中?
And an unerring capacity for getting his shipmates into trouble?
他确实长着尖耳朵
He did have pointed ears.
沿新航线前进  曲速7  以当前速度6.7小时内到达
Following new course. Warp 7. Arrival in 6.7 hours at present speed.
既然我们已经出发了  我现在向船上
Now that we're underway,
余下的船员宣布我此行的目的
I'll announce my intentions to the rest of the ship.
进取号星舰上勇敢的船员们  想想存在的问题吧
Brave crew ofthe starship Enterprise, consider the questions ofexistence.
这是自人类第一次凝望星空
Questions that man has asked
自梦想诞生以来就已提出的问题
since he first gazed at the stars and dreamed.
我的瓦肯祖先们受他们的情感所支配
My Vulcan ancestors were ruled by their emotions.
他们用心去感受
They felt with their hearts.
他们用心去爱  他们用心去信仰
They made love with their hearts. They believed with their hearts.
而且他们相信有一个能解答这些问题的地方
And they believed in a place where these questions would be answered.
现代信条告诉我们这地方是虚构的
Modern dogma tells us this place is a myth.
是由异教徒编造出来的幻想
A fantasy concocted by pagans.
这不是幻想
Itis no fantasy.
我告诉你们...这地方真的存在
I tell you...it exists.
兄弟们  我们被选中
My brothers, we have been chosen
去进行有史以来最伟大的冒险
to undertake the greatest adventure of all time.
去探索沙・卡・里
The discovery of Sha Ka Ree.
他为了寻找沙・卡・里而离开瓦肯
Is it possible he's found Sha Ka Ree,
他有没有可能找到它了?
the reason he left Vulcan?
我们的目的地是沙・卡・里星球
Our destination is the planet Sha Ka Ree.
它存在于大屏障之后...
It lies beyond the Great Barrier...
...在银河系的中心
..at the centre ofthe galaxy.
在银河系的中心?  传说中它所存在的地方
The centre of the galaxy?. Where it is fabled to exist.
没有哪艘飞船能到达银河系中心
The centre of the galaxy can't be reached by any ship.
赛波克是我所知道的最有智慧的人
Sybok possessed the keenest intellect I've ever known.
等我夺回飞船  把赛波克关到这儿...
When I get the ship back, and Sybok is in here,
你再慢慢和他争论沙・卡・里  直到脸上发绿都行
you can debate Sha Ka Ree until you're green in the face.
你要么站在我这边要么别站我这边
You're either with me or you're not.
我在这里  舰长  说得有点含糊  史波克
I am here, Captain. That's a little vague, Spock.
那是什么声音?
What's that noise?
这是一种叫摩尔斯电码的通讯形式
It's a primitive form of communication known as Morse Code.
你说得对  我很久没接触过这个了  这是S
You're right. I'm out of practice. That's an S.
T...  A...
T... A...
N...  D...  单词结束
N... D... End of word.
Stand  新词
Stand. New word.
B...  A...
B... A...
C...  K...
C... K...
靠后站!
Back. Stand back!
你们干嘛站在边上?  这是在越狱
What are you standing around for?. This is a jailbreak.
这三个人很坚定  真是个挑战
These three are strong. This will be quite a challenge.
我们得找到他们
We've got to find them.
我们谁也不能信  我们可以发送求救信号
We can't trust anyone. Send a distress signal.
观察室里有一台紧急发送机
There is an emergency send apparatus in the observation room.
你们可以通过3号涡轮管道到达那里
You might be able to reach it by means of Turbo-shaft 3.
爬上去要很久  而且很危险  某些人就是爱这个
It's a long and dangerous climb. Some of us get off on that.
修好传送机并联络救援飞船
Get the transporter working and contact a rescue ship.
去涡轮管道走哪条路?  沿那条通道走然后右转
Which way to the Turbo-shaft? Down that tunnel and turn right.
你一定会找到的  史考特先生  你真棒
You can't miss it. Mr Scott, you're amazing.
我对这艘飞船了如指掌
I know this ship like the back of my hand.
我们可以好好锻炼下了  对  或者患个心脏病
We'll get a good workout. Yeah, or a heart attack.
快把史考特先生送去医务室
Get Mr Scott to sick bay.
好像一辈子都爬不完这个
This is going to take me forever.
史波克在哪里?
Where's Spock?.
我相信我找到了更快的方法
I believe I've found a faster way.
老骨头?  我等下一辆车
Bones? I'll wait for the next car.
我们绝不分开
We're not splitting up.
我们太重了  肯定是吃了太多的沼泽甜瓜
We're too heavy. It must be the marsh melons.
史波克  助推器  我无法控制能量
Spock, the booster rockets. I can't control their power.
启动助推器
Fire the rockets.
舰长  请下来
Captain, please come back down.
按下控制器
Hit the brakes.
我飞高了一层  没有人是完美的
I overshot the mark by one level. Nobody's perfect.
史波克
Spock.
紧急频道开启
Emergency channel open.
通信范围内的任何人  我是詹姆斯T.柯克舰长
To anyone within range, this is Captain James T Kirk.
收到请回复
If you read me, acknowledge.
回复
Acknowledge.
这里是星际舰队指挥部  收到讯息  完毕
This is Starfleet Command, we readyou. Over.
一伙敌意分子控制了我们的飞船
A hostile force has taken control of our vessel.
我们的方位是000.2  请求紧急援助
Our co-ordinates are 000.2. Request emergency assistance.
明白  进取号  我们立即派遣一艘救援飞船
Understood, Enterprise. We are dispatching a rescue ship immediately.
设定航线000.2
Plot course 000.2.
但这样的话我们也会驶向大屏障
But Captain, that course will take us into the Barrier as well.
柯克去哪  我们就去哪
Where Kirk goes, we follow.
相信你们的讯息已经被收到了  你别指望我们不会采取行动
I trust your message was received. You can't expect us to stand by.
你对未知感到恐惧
What you fear is the unknown.
你们星球上的人曾相信他们的世界是平的
The people of your planet once believed their world was flat.
哥伦布证明了它是圆的
Columbus proved it was round.
他们曾说音障不可能被打破  它被打破了
They said the sound barrier could never be broken. It was broken.
他们曾说曲速不可能达到
They said warp speed could not be achieved.
大屏障是这种普遍恐惧的终极表现
The Great Barrier is the ultimate expression of this universal fear.
这是个人恐惧感的延伸
It is an extension of personal fear.
柯克舰长  我是多么希望你能理解
Captain Kirk, I so much want your understanding.
我想要你尊重我  你害怕听我把话说完?
I want your respect. Are you afraid to hear me out?
我什么都不怕  在外面等
I'm afraid of nothing. Wait outside.
我能肯定你有许多问题
I'm sure you have many questions.
来  在我们银河的群星之中...
Here, amidst the stars of our own galaxy,
让我们共同探索答案
we shall seek the answers together.
放松  史考提  你没事了
Easy, Scotty. You're back with us.
我梦见一个疯子占领了进取号
I dreamt that a madman had taken over the Enterprise.
他不是疯子  不是?
He's not a madman. He's not?
赛波克让我们接触到了我们一直害怕表达的那些情感
Sybok has put us in touch with feelings we've always been afraid to express.
我得去修传送机了  史考提!
I have to get to the transporter. Scotty!
我有太多事要对你说  等我稍微好些再说吧
There's so much I want to tell you. Wait till I'm a wee bit stronger.
我觉得以我目前的情况无法理解关于他的...或你的事
I don't think I could take it in my present condition...or yours.
沙・卡・里  源头
Sha Ka Ree. The Source.
天堂
Heaven.
伊甸园  随你怎么称呼
Eden. Call it what you will.
克林贡人叫它奎突
The Klingons call it Qui Tu.
罗幕兰人叫它沃塔・沃  安多利人的叫法难以发音
The Romulans, Vorta Vor. In Andorian it is unpronounceable.
但是  每一个文明都分享着这个共同点梦想
Still, every culture shares this common dream.
那里是万物的源泉  对我们来说它很快就会变为现实
A place from which creation sprang. For us it will soon be reality.
我唯一的现实就是我成了自己飞船上的囚犯
My only reality is that I'm a prisoner on my own ship.
你用什么能力控制船员的思想的?
What is this power you have to control the minds of my crew?.
我并不控制思想...我是释放思想
I don't control minds... I free them.
怎么释放?
How?.
让你面对你内心的痛苦并从中获得力量
By making you face your pain and draw strength from it.
一旦完成了  你就不会再恐惧了
Once that's done, fear cannot stop you.
听上去就像洗脑
It sounds like brainwashing to me.
你是所有人中最痛苦的
Your pain is the deepest of all.
我能感觉到  你呢?
I can feel it, can't you?
罗纳德
Leonard.
这肯定是某种诡计
This is some kind of trick.
罗纳德
Leonard.
父亲?  上帝啊!  别对我这么做
Father?. My God! Don't do this to me.
罗纳德
Leonard.
我在这儿  我就在你身边  父亲
I'm here. I'm with you, Dad.
痛苦  结束我这种痛苦吧
The pain. Stop the pain.
我已经尽力了  你得撑住啊
I've done everything I can do. You've got to hang on.
我受不了这种痛苦了
I can't stand the pain.
帮帮我
Help me.
我竭尽全力还是救不了他
All my knowledge and I can't save him.
你已经尽力而为了  生命维持系统能让他活下去的
You've done all you can. The support system will keep him alive.
你把这叫活下去?  儿子...
You call this alive? Son...
让我解脱吧  我不能那么做  父亲
Release me. I can't do that, Dad.
但我怎么忍心看他这样受苦?
But how can I watch him suffer like this?
你是个医生
You're a doctor.
我是他儿子
I'm his son.
你为什么这么做?
Why did you do it?
维持他的尊严
To preserve his dignity.
那还不是最糟的  对吗?  对!
That wasn't the worst of it, was it? No!
那么分享最糟的
Share it.
不久以后  他们发现一种疗法  一种该死的疗法
Not long after, they found a cure. A goddamn cure.
如果你不杀他  他就还能活着  我让他解脱了!
If you didn't kill him, he'd have lived. I released him!
你做了你以为是正确的事  是的!  不!
You did what you thought was right. Yes! No!
从痛苦中解脱吧!
Release this pain!
这种痛苦长久以来毒害着你的灵魂
This pain has poisoned your soul for a long time.
现在你迈出了第一步
Now you've taken the first step.
让我们一起走完剩下的路
The other steps we'll take together.
每个人的痛苦都是独特的
Each man's pain is unique.
我没有什么隐藏的痛苦
I hide no pain.
我比你以为的更了解你  是吗?
I know you better than that. Do you?
史波克  别  没关系  舰长
Spock, don't. It's all right, Captain.
继续
Proceed.
这是什么?  我相信我们正在目睹我的出生
What is this? I believe we are witnessing my birth.
萨瑞克  你的儿子
Sarek, your son.
真像人类
So human.
史波克?
Spock?.
你对我的朋友做了些什么?  没什么  他们就是这样
What have you done to my friends? Nothing. This is who they are.
你不知道?  对  我不知道
Didn't you know that? No, I didn't.
现在了解一下你自己吧  不  我不干
Now learn something about yourself. No, I refuse.
吉姆  试着对这个开明一点  对哪个?
Jim, try to be open about this. About what?
我在人生中怎么作了错误的决定?  怎么走错了人生道路?
How I made wrong choices in my life? Turning left instead of right?
我不需要赛波克带着我游览自己的虚弱之处
I don't need Sybok to take me on a tour of my weaknesses.
这是在被骗子洗脑!
To be brainwashed by a conman!
这个骗子去除了我的痛苦  仅仅魔杖一挥就去除了痛苦?
This conman took away my pain. With the wave of a magic wand?
我们所经历过的事造就了我们
The things we carry with us make us who we are.
如果我们失去了这些  我们就迷失了自我
If we lose them, we lose ourselves.
我不想去掉我的痛苦  我需要这些痛苦
I don't want my pain taken away. I need my pain.
舰长  你继续待在这儿
Captain, you remain here.
史波克  麦考依医生  跟我来
Spock, Dr McCoy, come with me.
史波克?  我不能跟你走
Spock?. I cannot go with you.
为什么?  我属于这里
Why not? I belong here.
我不明白  赛波克...
I don't understand. Sybok...
你是我的兄弟  但你并不了解我
You are my brother, but you do not know me.
我不是你多年前丢下的那个被遗弃的小男孩了
I am not the outcast boy you left behind many years ago.
我找回了自我和自己的位置  我知道我是什么样的人
I found myself and my place, and I know who I am.
我不能跟你走
I cannot go with you.
你最好也别叫我跟你走
You'd better count me out, too.
那么我只好在大屏障另一边跟你们再见了  等等!
Then I'll see you on the other side. Wait!
我们不可能成功穿越大屏障
We'll never make it through the Great Barrier.
如果成功了  能使你相信我的观点是正确的吗?
If we do, will that convince you that my vision was true?
是上帝在指使我  他在大屏障另一边等着我们
It was given to me by God. He waits for us on the other side.
你疯了
You are mad.
是吗?
Am l?
我们走着瞧
We'll see.
他们说没有飞船能够幸存
They say no ship can survive this.
他们错了  危险是一种假象
They're wrong. Danger is an illusion.
我们的仪表全都没读数了
We have no instrument readings.
苏鲁先生  全速前进  全速前进  明白
Mr Sulu, full ahead. Full ahead, aye.
这怎么可能?  太神奇了
Is it possible? Fascinating.
我们在做梦吗?
Are we dreaming?
如果是的  那么人生就是一场梦
If we are, then life is a dream.
(大胆踏迹前人未至之地)
仪表重新恢复了
Instruments are back on line.
不可思议
Incredible.
这个星球发出一种我从没见过的能源
There is a power source emanating from the planet like nothing I've seen.
沙・卡・里  奎突
Sha Ka Ree. Qui Tu.
沃塔・沃
Vorta Vor.
伊甸园
Eden.
关于这艘飞船...  它需要舰长
About the ship... The ship needs its captain.
没有特殊条件?  没有
No special conditions? No conditions.
那我也许会让飞船调头回去
I could turn us around.
不  你太需要去了解这一切了
No, you too must know.
那  既然我们一定要这么做  就按着本本办事好了
Well, if we're going to do it, we're going to do it by the book.
标准轨道靠近  准备好穿梭机
Standard orbital approach. Alert the shuttlecraft to stand by.
赛波克  史波克  麦考依
Sybok, Spock, McCoy,
跟我来  其余人留在飞船上
come with me. The rest of you remain on board.
等我先搞清楚我们在跟什么打交道再说
Until I determine what we're dealing with.
别傻站着了  上帝可是个大忙人
Don't just stand there, God's a busy man.
穿梭机不受我控制了
I am no longer in control of the craft.
好吧  我们全听你的
All right, we'll play it your way.
真迷人  这大地  这天空
It's amazing. The land. The sky.
就像我心目中的一样
Just as I knew it would be.
史考提  你看看这个  我没时间
You have to see this. I don't have time.
舰长要我修好传送机
The Captain told me to get the transporter working.
我们乘坐星舰
We have travelled far.
远道而来
By starship.
进取号  我是柯克
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
我们已经...
We have...
赛波克
Sybok.
也许...
Perhaps...
欢迎  勇敢的灵魂
Brave souls, welcome.
这是上帝的声音吗?
Is this the voice of God?
一种声音  多张面庞
One voice, many faces.
是否这样更合乎你的期望?
Does this better suit your expectations?
你是谁?  我就是我
Qualse tu? It is l.
你们的旅程一定很不容易
Yourjourney could not have been an easy one.
是的  我们必须突破大屏障
It was not. We had to breach the Barrier.
了不起  你们是最先找到我的人
Magnificent. You are the first to find me.
我们来向你寻求无限的智慧  你们是怎么突破屏障的?
We sought only your infinite wisdom. How did you breach the Barrier?.
乘坐星舰  这艘星舰...
With a starship. This starship...
它能否将我的智慧带出屏障?
Could it carry my wisdom beyond the Barrier?.
是的  能够  那么我要用它
It could, yes. Then I shall make use of it.
它将成为您的马车  打扰一下...
It will be your chariot. Excuse me...
我将游遍宇宙的每个角落  我想问个问题
I will reach every corner of creation. I'd like to ask a question.
上帝要星舰干什么?  把这艘星舰驶近点
What does God need with a starship? Bring the ship closer.
上帝要星舰干什么?
What does God need with a starship?
你在干什么?  问问题
What are you doing? Asking a question.
这个生物是谁?  你不知道?  你不是上帝吗?
Who is this creature? Don't you know?. Aren't you God?
他有他的疑惑  你怀疑我?
He has his doubts. You doubt me?
我想要证明  你不能向全能的上帝要他的ID
I seek proof. You don't ask the Almighty for his ID.
那么这就是你想要的证明
Then here is the proof you seek.
上帝为什么生气?  你为什么这么做?
Why is God angry?. Why have you done this?
他怀疑我  你还没回答他的问题
He doubts me. You have not answered his question.
上帝要星舰干什么?
What does God need with a starship?
你也怀疑我?
Do you doubt me?
我怀疑所有那些将自己的快乐
I doubt any god
建立在别人的痛苦之上的上帝
who inflicts pain for his own pleasure.
住手!  沙・卡・里上帝是不会这么做的
Stop! The god of Sha Ka Ree would not do this.
沙・卡・里?  那是你自己创造的幻想
Sha Ka Ree? A vision you created.
长久以来我一直被囚禁在此
An eternity I've been imprisoned in this place.
飞船  我一定要得到飞船
The ship. I must have the ship.
现在...给我飞船
Now...give me what I want.
赛波克...
Sybok...
这不是沙・卡・里上帝  或其他任何上帝
This is not the god of Sha Ka Ree, or any other god.
我不明白  让我看看你的真面目
I don't understand. Reveal yourself to me.
怎么?  难道你不喜欢这张脸?
What's wrong? Don't you like this face?
我有那么多样子  这个最适合你
I have so many, but this one suits you best.
不  这不可能
No, it's not possible.
给我飞船  否则我就消灭你们  飞船
Bring me the ship or I will destroy you. The ship.
把它驶近点...这样我就能与它结合了
Bring it closer so that I might join with it.
照做  否则就看着这些微不足道的东西――
Do it, or watch these puny things
悲惨地死去
die horribly.
我做了什么?  进取号  仔细听好
What have I done? Enterprise, listen carefully.
这就是我的所作所为  是我的傲慢  自负
This is my doing. This is my arrogance. My vanity.
赛波克  我们必须想办法...  不  你们逃命吧
Sybok, we must find a way... No, save yourselves.
原谅我  兄弟
Forgive me, brother.
我虽然不能帮助  但注意到了你的痛苦
I couldn't help but notice your pain.
你的痛苦很深重  与我分享吧
It runs deep. Share it with me.
进取号  准备好了吗?  鱼雷已装载
Enterprise, are you ready?. Torpedo armed.
我们将向你们所在的位置发射  发射!
We're firing on your position. Send it down now!
快跑!
Run!
赛波克...
Sybok...
我们快离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
苏鲁  我失去他们了
Sulu, I've lost them.
史波克  带我们离开这儿
Spock, get us out of here.
推进器失灵了
Thrusters are inoperative.
史考特先生  请告诉我传送机已经修好了
Mr Scott, please tell me the transporter is working.
我现在可以传送两个人
I might be able to beam up two of you.
把史波克和麦考依医生传送上去  该死的等等!
Beam up Spock and Dr McCoy now. Just a damn minute!
把舰长带上来
Bring up the Captain.
我们不能把吉姆留在那里  关心你自己就行了  报告情况
We can't just leave Jim down there. Get a grip on yourself. Status report.
克林贡舰长想谈谈条件
The Klingon captain wishes to name his terms.
我是克林贡帝国的克拉舰长
This is Captain Klaa ofthe Klingon Empire.
不要企图装载武器  否则我就摧毁你们
Do not attempt to arm your weapons orl will destroy you.
你们现在还活着只是因为一个原因
You are alive for a single reason:
叛逆者詹姆斯T.柯克
the renegade James TKirk.
把他交出来我就饶了你们
Hand him over and I will spare your lives.
我已经准备好把他传送上舰了  柯克舰长不在我们这儿
I'm ready to beam him aboard. Captain Kirk is not among us.
你撒谎  瓦肯人不撒谎
You lie. Vulcans are incapable of lying.
柯克舰长在下面的星球上  那么给我他的坐标
Captain Kirk is on the planet below. Then give me his co-ordinates.
我需要你的帮助  我的帮助?
I am in need of your assistance. My assistance?
你是他的上司  我是个笨老头
You are his superior officer. I am a foolish old man.
见你的鬼  先生  你一定要试试
Damn you, sir. You will try.
克林贡指挥官  有人想和你说几句
Klingon commander, someone wishes to speak with you.
你们这帮混蛋要抓的是我
So it's me you want, you bastards.
你们还等什么?
What are you waiting for?.
放了他
Release him.
我的部下有话要跟你说
Myjunior officer has something he wants to say to you.
我...向你道歉
I...apologise.
对你们飞船的攻击没有得到我们政府的批准
The attack upon your vessel was not authorised by my government.
现在  请允许我介绍我们的新炮手
Now, may I present our new gunner.
史波克!  欢迎登舰  舰长
Spock! Welcome aboard, Captain.
我以为我死定了
I thought I was going to die.
不可能  你从不孤独
Not possible, you were never alone.
舰长  请不要在克林贡人面前这样
Please, Captain, not in front of the Klingons.
想不想呷一点点苏格兰威士忌?
Would you care for a wee nip of Scotch whisky?.
我从没想过自己会和一个克林贡人一起喝酒
I never thought I'd be drinking with a Klingon.
你们俩在密谋什么呢?  关于我们所取得的进展
What are you two conspiring about? About the progress we've made.
她的肌肉真不错
She has wonderful muscles.
在思考宇宙吗  先生们?
Cosmic thoughts, gentlemen?
我们在思索...真有上帝在那儿吗?
We were speculating... Is God really out there?
也许他不在那儿
Maybe he's not out there.
也许他在这儿  在人们心中
Maybe he's right here in the human heart.
史波克?  我在想赛波克
Spock?. I was thinking of Sybok.
我失去了一个兄弟  嗯
I have lost a brother. Yes.
我曾经失去一位兄弟
I lost a brother, once.
我很幸运  我把他带了回来
I was lucky. I got him back.
我记得你说过像我们这样的人没有家庭
I thought you said men like us don't have families.
我错了
I was wrong.
你只是要拨弄那东西呢  还是准备弹奏点什么?
Are you just going to pluck that thing, or are you going to play something?
划呀划  来划船
Row, row, row your boat
缓缓地顺流而下
Gently down the stream
欢快地  欢快地  欢快地  欢快地划
Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily
生命是梦想
Life is but a dream...